ANUP **DHAKAL**

Gwarko, Lalitpur ↑
9843768138 ↓
anupdhakal2000@gmail.com

exanup in



ABOUT ME

My main strengths include my confidence, diligence and my determination to always do my best. I have the ability to grasp concepts quickly. I have good experiences of working in various teams, leading and motivating team members and hence always trying to get the best out of everyone for maximum efficiency. I am well motivated and always prepared to get trained and learn further to benefit any organization I work for, as well as, to fulfill my very own potential.



EDUCATION

B.E. Computer | Kantipur Engineering College (T.U.), Dhapakhel, Lalitpur 2013 – 2016 (RESULTS AWAITING)

Till now, aggregate score is around 65%, degree not achieved yet.

Optional subjects I chose were Data Mining, Big Data, and XML.

Minor project: Game development framework. My major contribution was the map editor for the framework developed in Python programming language.

Major project: Titled: "Eloquent Fix On". My major contribution on the project was a Python based web scrapper and a Laravel (PHP) based consumer faced web application.

+2 Science | Shikshadeep H.S.S., Biratnagar, Morang

2011 - 2012

Aggregate score: 68%

S.L.C. | Shikshadeep H.S.S., Biratnagar, Morang

2001 - 2010

Score in S.L.C.: 87%



EXPERIENCE

Sales Engineer (Business Support) | Microsoft Operations Pte. Ltd., Kathmandu FEB 2017 – JAN 2018

Following were some of the responsibilities that I undertook:

- Basically "look after" all the operations of Microsoft in Nepal and Bhutan under the mentorship of Mr. Deependra Bajracharya (Business Development)
- Pre-sales technical support; sales engineer
- Design highly scalable and efficient, yet secure and private enterprise cloud based solutions on

Microsoft Azure and on-premises Microsoft platform

• Licensing and legalization of Microsoft products

C.T.O. | Technorio Inc. Pvt. Ltd., Kathmandu JAN 2016 – DEC 2016

Following were some of the tasks that fell under my scope in the then startup organization as the "self-proclaimed", if you will :), C.T.O.:

- Take decisions regarding the technologies the company needed to adapt to, to modern needs and demands, and hence drive the organization towards its vision
- Take informed decision based on the current resources in the company, hence compromising to find the balance between "the best" and "the cheapest" and, as a result, determine "the most feasible" options for the organization
- Full-stack development of web based applications and REST APIs
- Design and optimize the database in MySQL, MariaDB and PostgreSQL
- "Doing things right vs. doing right things!" Verification and validation against the requirements



SKILLS

- Problem Solving by Critical Thinking
- Requirement Analysis
- Cloud Computing SaaS

- Python
- JavaScript
- Laravel



OTHER ACTIVITIES

I love teaching. As one of my teaching experiences, I have provided Python core programming training as a trainer in Everest Engineering and Management College, Buddhanagar, for final year students.

Also, I have recently been to Hetauda City College (B.I.T.), Hetauda, as a guest speaker for a workshop on "Project Management"; my contribution being on topics related to importance of project management and how-to's of handling a project elegantly and efficiently.

I love watching football. I follow Manchester City F.C. and I absolutely adore Pep Guardiola and his philosophy for the game. FIFA and Minecraft are my favourite games. I like to stay fit and hit the gym regularly.